Guide to the Louis Durr Print Collection 1513–1835, undated (bulk, 1660s) PR 142
New-York Historical Society
Louis Durr print collection
1513–1835, undated (bulk, 1660s)
New-York Historical Society
Durr, Louis, 1821-1880
PR 142
252 item(s) in 3 boxes and 3 oversize folders.
A collection of European engravings, over half of which consists of leaves disbound from the catalog Theatrum Pictorium, compiled in the 1660s by the painter David Teniers, which depicts paintings from the collection of his patron, Leopold Wilhelm, Archduke of Austria. Most of the paintings represented are Italian, by the artists Titian, Giorgione, Polidoro da Lanciano, Tintoretto, Veronese, Andrea Schiavone, Francesco Bassano, Francesco Bassano the Younger, Palma il Giovane, Palma il Vecchio, and Domenico Fetti. Engravers include Coryn Boel, Nikolaus van Hoy, Theodor van Kessel, Pieter van Lisebetten, Jan van Ossenbeeck, Lucas Vorsterman II, and Johannes Popels. The collection includes an additional 94 European engravings from other sources, mostly after religious or allegorical works by Leonardo da Vinci, Raphael, Rembrandt, Sir Joshua Reynolds, Rubens, Titian, and Anthony Van Dyck. Three prints show sculptures by Antonio Canova. There are also two works by Albrecht Dürer. Engravers include Francesco Bartolozzi, Pietro Fontana, Domenico Marchetti, Raffaello Morghen, and Lucas Vorsterman.
Arrangement
The collection is organized in two series:
Series I.
Leaves from the Theatrum Pictorium, 1660s
Series II.
Other engravings, 1513–1835, undated
In the container list below, the numbers preceding each print were assigned by New-York Historical Society staff when the collection was accessioned. Titles in quotes and attributions were transcribed directly from the prints. Brief descriptions in [square brackets] were supplied for those prints without titles in the plate.
Biographical note
Louis Durr was born in Germany in 1821. His father was a jeweler; the young Durr first learned about art from his father and his wealthy clients. In 1848 Durr moved to the United States with his brother. He worked in Brooklyn and at a gold smeltery in Newark, New Jersey before starting his own business as a gold and silver refiner and assayer in New York City. Durr remained interested in art, and used his growing wealth to build a formidable collection of European paintings, which was particularly strong in the Dutch school. In 1863 he purchased a house on Fourth Street in Manhattan in which to store and display his artwork. It was Durr's intention to leave his collection to the City of New York, but its bulk proved difficult in the quest to secure a willing repository. After his death in 1880, several works of art, including engravings, were auctioned. The majority of the remainder of Durr's art collection was then given to the New-York Historical Society.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers by appointment only. To schedule an appointment, contact the Print Room Librarian at printroom@nyhistory.org.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Twenty-two engravings were purchased, 1882. The remaining prints were a gift of the Durr estate, 1882.
Related Materials
The Louis Durr Print Collection is similar in scope to the Bryan Gallery of Christian Art Print Collection (PR-143).
The New-York Historical Society's Museum holds a number of paintings from Louis Durr's Collection.
Scope and Contents
The Louis Durr Print Collection spans the period 1513 to 1835 and contains European engravings.
Series I. Leaves from the Theatrum Pictorium, 1660s contains 158 disbound leaves from the book of that name (alternately titled Le theatre des peintures, or Amphitheatrum picturarum) compiled in the 1660s by the painter David Teniers. A second edition with page numbers was published in 1673. The paintings depicted in the book are from the art collection of Leopold Wilhelm, the Archduke of Austria (1614–1662), Teniers' patron. Most of the painters represented are Italian, and include Titian (circa 1488–1576), Giorgione (1477 or 1478–1510), Polidoro da Lanciano (?–1565), Tintoretto (1518–1594), Paolo Veronese (1528–1588), Andrea Schiavone (circa 1500–1563), Francesco Bassano (circa 1470–circa 1539), Palma il Giovane (1544–1628), Palma il Vecchio (1480?–1528), and Domenico Fetti (circa 1589–1623). Teniers himself made small copies of these paintings from which the engravings were executed. The book includes many different engravers, such as Coryn Boel (1620–1668), Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679), Jan van Kessel (1641–1680), Peter van Lisebetten (1630–1678), Jan van Ossenbeeck (1624?–1674), Lucas Vorsterman (1624–circa 1666), and Johannes Popels (1590–1663). The engravings in the Theatrum pictorium were grouped roughly chronologically by painter; the New-York Historical Society numbers assigned to these engravings follow a loosely alphabetical organization by engraver. A separate listing of the engravings by plate number has been created as well. The complete book contains 246 leaves. The missing leaves may have been sold at the auction of Durr's estate. A few leaves have two small engravings on one page; several other engravings are double leaves.
Series II. Other engravings, 1513–1835, undated encompasses 94 diverse European prints. Most of these engravings are religious or allegorical works after Peter Paul Rubens (1577–1640), Titian (circa 1488–1576), Sir Joshua Reynolds (1723–1792), Raphael (1483–1520), Rembrandt (1606–1669), Anthony Van Dyck (1599–1641), and Leonardo da Vinci (1452–1519). Three prints show sculptures by Antonio Canova (1757–1822). Two works by Albrecht Dürer (1471–1528) are included. Engravers highly represented include Lucas Vorsterman (1624–circa 1666), Francesco Bartolozzi (1727–1815), Pietro Fontana (1762–1837), Raffaelo Morghen (1761–1833), and Domenico Marchetti (1780–1844).
Engravings (prints); Christian art and symbolism.; Prints -- Belgium -- 17th century.; Prints -- Belgium -- 18th century.; Prints -- Italy -- 17th century.; Prints -- Italy -- 18th century.; Prints -- Collectors and collecting -- United States.; Bartolozzi, Francesco, 1727-1815; Bassano, Francesco, approximately 1470-approximately 1539; Boel, Coryn, 1620-1668; Canova, Antonio, 1757-1822; Dürer, Albrecht, 1471-1528; Eynhoudts, Remoldus, 1613-1679 or 1680; Fetti, Domenico, approximately 1589-1623; Fontana, Pietro, 1762-1837; Giorgione, 1477 or 1478-1510; Hoey, Nicolas de; Kessel, Jan van, 1641-1680; Lauwers, Conrad, approximately 1632-approximately 1685; Leonardo, da Vinci, 1452-1519; Leopold Wilhelm, Archduke of Austria, 1614-1662 -- Art collections.; Lisebetten, Pieter van, 1630-1678; Marchetti, Domenico (Engraver); Morghen, Raffaello, 1761-1833; Ossenbeeck, Jan van, 1624?-1674; Palma, il Giovane, 1544-1628; Palma, il Vecchio, 1480?-1528; Polidoro, da Lanciano, -1565; Popels, Johannes; Raphael, 1483-1520; Rembrandt Harmenszoon van Rijn, 1606-1669; Reynolds, Joshua, Sir, 1723-1792; Rubens, Peter Paul, 1577-1640; Schiavone, Andrea, approximately 1500-1563; Teniers, David, 1610-1690 -- Theatrum Pictorium; Tintoretto, 1518-1594; Titian, approximately 1488-1576; Van Dyck, Anthony, 1599-1641; Veronese, 1528-1588; Vorsterman, Lucas, 1624-approximately 1666
- Series I. Leaves from the Theatrum Pictorium, 1660s
  Arrangement
  In Series I, the numbers in [square brackets] preceding each print were assigned by New-York Historical Society staff when the collection was accessioned. This numbering system is organized alphabetically by engraver, except for where two plates printed on the same sheet (indicated by "a" and "b") break the alphabetical run.
  The N-YHS numbering system bears no relation to the accepted ordering of the 246 images in the complete Theatrum Pictorium. Where known, these latter numbers have been supplied in {curly brackets} following title, artist, and engraver information. Interested researchers should consult https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Theatrum_Pictorium.
  - Engraved by Coryn Boel (1620–1668)
    - [001] [Old Age in Search of Youth] after Corregio (circa 1489–1534) {031}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - [002] [Seduction and landscape] after Giorgione (1477–1510) {017}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - [003] [Calling of the Sons of Zebedee] after Marco Basaiti (circa 1470–1530) {010}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - [004] [Hercules, Deianira and the Centaur Nessus] after Paolo Veronese (1528–1588) {115}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - [005a] [St. Nicholas] after Tintoretto / Paolo Veronese (1528–1588), engraved by Pieter van Lisebetten (1630–1678) {111}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - [005b] [Saint John Agnus Dei] after Paolo Veronese (1528–1588) {112}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - [006] [Carrying the Cross] after Giovanni Cariani (circa 1485–after 1547) {166}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - [007] [St. Hieronymous] after Dosso Dossi (circa 1489–1542) {232}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - [008] [Angel tied up] after Domenico Fetti (circa 1589–1623) {221}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - [009] [Perseus freeing Andromeda] after Domenico Fetti (circa 1589–1623) {219}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - [010] [Galatea and Polyphem] after Domenico Fetti (circa 1589–1623) {220}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 1)
    - [011] [Tobit and Tobias burying the dead Israelite] after Domenico Fetti (circa 1589–1623) {216}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - [012] [Blind leading the Blind] after Domenico Fetti (circa 1589–1623) {215}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - [013] [Tobit and the Dead Israelite] after Domenico Fetti (circa 1589–1623) {214}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - [014] [Lazarus] after Palma il Vecchio (circa 1480–1528) {188}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - [015] [Saint Jerome] after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {170}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - [016] [Shepherds in a pasture] after Francesco Bassano (circa 1470–1539) {151}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - [017] [The Good Samaritan] after Francesco Bassano (circa 1470–1539) {152}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - [018] [Building a Tower / Tower of Babel] after Leandro Bassano (1557–1622) {154}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - [019] [Adoration of the Shepherds] after Andrea Schiavone (circa 1510–1563) {134}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - [020] "Aeneas called away from Dido," after Andrea Schiavone (circa 1510–1563) {137}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 2)
    - [021] [Marius Curius Dentatus] after Andrea Schiavone (circa 1510–1563) {136}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
    - [022] [Scipio Africanus] after Andrea Schiavone (circa 1510–1563) {138}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
    - [023] [Adam and Eve] after Alessandro Padovanino (1588–1648) {036}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
    - [024] [Virgin and Child accompanied by St. John and an Angel] after Giulio Cesare Procaccini (1574–1625) {033}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Engraved by Remoldus Eynhoudts (1613–1679 or 1680)
    - [025] [Christ Resurrected] after Palma il Vecchio (circa 1480–1528) {174}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
    - [026] [Christ mourned by Angels] after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {198}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Engraved by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679)
    - [027] [Holy Family] after Federico Barocci (circa 1535–1612) {034}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
    - [028] [Judith with the Head of Holofernes] after Paolo Veronese (1528–1588) {113}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
    - [029] [Lamentation] after Domenico Fetti (circa 1589–1623) {218}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
    - [030a] [Portrait of man] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {050}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Engraved by Lucas Vorsterman II (1624–circa 1666)
    - [030b] [Salome with the Head of John the Baptist] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {051}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Engraved by Wenceslaus Hollar (1607–1677)
    - [031] "Esther before Ahasureus," after Paolo Veronese (1528–1588) {125}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Engraved by Theodor van Kessel (1620–1696)
    - [032] [Toilet of Venus] after Corregio (circa 1489–1534) {030}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - [033] [Ascension of Christ] after Giorgione (1477–1510) {022}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - [034] [Rape of Europa] after Giorgione (1477–1510) {018}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - [035] [The Holy Family in a Landscape with John the Baptist] after Paris Bordone (1500–1571) {210}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - [036] [Saint Sebastian] after Paolo Veronese (1528–1588) {114}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - [037] [Venus and Adonis] after Paolo Veronese (1528–1588) {116}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - [038] [Christ and the Adulteress] after Annibale Carracci (1560–1609) {043}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - [039] [Christ and the Woman from Samaria] after Annibale Carracci (1560–1609) {042}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - [040] "Apollo and Marsyas," after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {201}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 4)
    - [041] [Adoration of the Shepherds] after Francesco Bassano the Younger (1549–1592) {161}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - [042] [Christ carrying cross] after Jacopo Bassano (circa 1510–1592) {156}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - [043] [Adoration of the Magi] after Jacopo Bassano (circa 1510–1592) {153}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - [044] [Resurrection] after Francesco Bassano the Younger (1549–1592) {147}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - [045] [Susanna, partly naked and stepping out of a fountain with two elders at left, one of them pulling at her garment] after Guido Reni (1575–1642) {227}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - [046] [Birth of Jupiter] after Andrea Schiavone (circa 1510–1563) {132}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - [047] [Apollo and Eros] after Andrea Schiavone (circa 1510–1563) {126}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - [048] [Apollo and Daphne] after Andrea Schiavone (circa 1510–1563) {129}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - [049] [Jupiter nurtured by Amalthea] after Andrea Schiavone (circa 1510–1563) {128}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - [050] [Pastoral] after Tintoretto (1518–1594) {105}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 5)
    - [051] [Diana and Callisto] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {096}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - [052] [Adoration of the Magi] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {077}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - Engraved by Conrad Lauwers (circa 1632–circa 1685)
    - [053] [Holy Family] after Andrea Schiavone (circa 1510–1563) {130}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - [054] [Aeneas Fleeing Troy] after Andrea Schiavone (circa 1510–1563) {131}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
  - Engraved by Pieter van Lisebetten (1630–1678)
    - [055] [Pala di San Cassiano Madonna and Child] after Giovanni Bellini (circa 1430–1516) {005}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - [056] [Venus and Amor] after Paris Bordone (1500–1571) {211}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - [057] [Adam and Eve] after Paris Bordone (1500–1571) {209}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - [058] "Venus and Mars with Cupid," after Paris Bordone (1500–1571) {212}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - [059] [Sacrifice of Isaac] after Paolo Veronese (1528–1588) {119}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - [060] [Mystic Marriage of St. Catherine] after Paolo Veronese (1528–1588) {120}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 6)
    - [061] [Ascension of Christ] after Paolo Veronese (1528–1588) {117}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - [062] "Lamentation of Christ" [Pieta], after Aniballe Carracci (1560–1609) {040}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - [063] [Virgin and Child with Mystical Betrothal of St. Catherine with Saints Dominic and Peter] after Domenico Fetti (circa 1589–1623) {222}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - [064] [Arrest of Christ] after Bartolomeo Manfredi (circa 1582–1622) {234}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - [065] "Madonna and Child with Sts," after Palma il Vecchio (circa 1480–1528) {203}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - [066] [Visitation] after Palma il Vecchio (circa 1480–1528) {208}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - [067] [Saint Mary of Egypt in the Desert] after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {173}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - [068] [Cain and Abel] after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {178}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - [069] [Cain and Abel] after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {202}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - [070] "Madonna and Child with John the Baptist," after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {177}, 1660s (Offsite-box 1, Folder 7)
    - [071] "Apollo and Marsyas" [Apollo punished Marsyas], after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {200}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
    - [072] [Lamentation] after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {204}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
    - [073] [Holy Family], after Polidoro da Lanciano (circa 1515–1565) {046}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
    - [074] [Holy Family] after Polidoro da Lanciano (circa 1515–1565) {047}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
    - [075] [Madonna and Child with St. John] after Polidoro da Lanciano (circa 1515–1565) {048}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
    - [076] [Holy Family], after Polidoro da Lanciano (circa 1515–1565) {045}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
    - [077] [Moses tapping the rock] after Francesco Primaticcio (1504–1570) {038}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
    - [078] [Susanna and the Elders], after Guido Reni (1575–1642) {233}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
    - [079] [Holy Family with little John the Baptist and a saint] after Andrea Schiavone (circa 1510–1563) {140}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
    - [080] [Jesus with shepherd?] after Tintoretto (1518–1594) {100}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 8)
    - [081] [Christ on the Mount of Olives] after Tintoretto (1518–1594) {099}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
    - [082] "Descent from the Cross," after Tintoretto (1518–1594) {109}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
    - [083] [Horned Moses and the Tablets of the Law] after Valentin de Boulogne (1591–1632) {240}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
    - [084] [Little Tambourine Player] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {080}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
    - [085] [Christ at Emmaus] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {072}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
    - [086] [Death of Actaeon] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {073}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
    - [087] [Adoration of the Magi] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {068}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
    - [088] [Madonna and Child with St. Dorothy] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {065}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
    - [089] [Danae receiving the Shower of Gold] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {074}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
    - [090] "Nymph and Shepherd," after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {060}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 9)
  - Engraved by Jan van Ossenbeeck (1623–1674)
    - [091] [Diana taking revenge on Niobe for the death of her children] after Palma il Vecchio (circa 1480–1528), drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {189}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
    - [092] [Man and woman in forest] after Polidoro da Lanciano (circa 1515–1565), drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {035}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
    - [093] [Orpheus Charming the Animals] after Francesco Bassano the Younger (1549–1592), drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {155}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
    - [094] [Winter?] [Holy Family with manger] after Bassano, drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {160}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
    - [095] "Summer" [Summer with the Sacrifice of Isaac] after Francesco Bassano the Younger (1549–1592), drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {159}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
    - [096] [Spring and Banishment from Paradise] after Francesco Bassano the Younger (1549–1592), drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {157}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
    - [097] [Autumn with Moses and 10 Commandments] after Francesco Bassano the Younger (1549–1592), drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {158}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
    - [098] [St. Sebastian] after Bassano, drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {143}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
    - [099] [Gathering of Manna] after Tintoretto (1518–1594), drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {107}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
    - [100] [Flight into Egypt] after Tintoretto (1518–1594), drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {108}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 10)
  - Engraved by Johannes Popels (1590–1663)
    - [101] "Young Woman at Her Toilette" [Giovane donna nuda allo specchio] after Giovanni Bellini (circa 1430–1516) {007}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
    - [102a] [St. Sebastian] after Palma il Vecchio (circa 1480–1528) {167}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
    - [102b] [Saint John the Baptist] after Palma il Vecchio (circa 1480–1528) {168}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
    - [103] [Nursing Madonna with Sts Catherine and John the Baptist] after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {199}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
    - [104] "Christ supported by an Angel" [Dead Christ Supported by an Angel] after Palma il Giovane (circa 1548–1628) {179}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
    - [105] [Dead Christ supported by Angels] after Andrea Schiavone (circa 1510–1563) {133}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
  - Engraved by Franciscus van der Steen (circa 1625–1672)
    - [106] [Dream of Life] after Michelangelo (1475–1564), drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {012}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
    - [107] "View of Archduke's Stallberg gallery" [View into the picture gallery of the Archduke Leopold] after David Teniers the Younger (1610–1690), drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {245}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
    - [108] [Soldiers Playing Cards] after Bartolomeo Manfredi (1582–1622), drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {235}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
    - [109] [Holy Family] after Andrea del Sarto (1486–1530), drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {032}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
    - [110] [Christ and the Woman Taken in Adultery] after Alessandro Leone Varotari (Il Padovanino) (1588–1649), drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {237}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 11)
    - [111a] [The Madonna and Child with the Infant Saint John the Baptist and Saint Anthony Abbot] after Titian (circa 1488–1576), drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {061}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
  - Engraved by Lucas Vorsterman II (1624–circa 1666)
    - [111b] [Holy Family and John the Baptist] after Titian (circa 1488–1576) {062}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
  - Engraved by Franciscus van der Steen (circa 1625–1672)
    - [112] [The Madonna and Child with the Infant Saint John the Baptist and Saint Anthony Abbot] after Titian (circa 1488–1576), drawn by Nikolaus van Hoy (1631–1679) {071}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
  - Engraved by Jan van Troyen (1610–1670)
    - [113] [Penitent Mary Magdalene] after Corregio (circa 1489–1534) {029}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
    - [114] "Three Philosophers" after Giorgione (1477–1510) {020}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
    - [115] [Glorification of a Saint with Angels / The assumption of St. Catherine of Alexandria] after Giovanni Baglione (1566–1643) {236}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
    - [116] [Madonna and Child with Saints Lucy and Catherine and 2 Nuns] after Paolo Veronese (1528–1588) {121}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
    - [117] "Raising of the Youth of Nain" [Raising the Young Man of Nain] after Paolo Veronese (1528–1588) {124}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)
    - [118] [Cupid overcoming Pan] after Aniballe Carracci (1560–1609) {041}, 1660s (Offsite-box 2, Folder 12)